留堂 唉
Bfff... Detention. Uh!
我爱死这首歌了！
I love this song! Yea... Braagagaga...
神子
Miko.
你不是要做历史报告吗？
I thought you had a history report to do.
老师提前下课了？
Did detention end early?
我自己提前的
It did for me.
啊喔 老师追出来了
Aho, here comes teacher
她脸色不太好
and she doesn't look happy.
快踩油门 隔板！
Step on it, Bulkhead!
唉 神子啊
Eh, Miko.
神子 我是你的保镖
Miko, I'm supposed to be your guardian
不是你的逃学专车
not your get-away car.
你可不能逃课啊
You can't just cut detention.
你父母知道了怎么办？
What if your parents found out?
他们在东京呢 忘了吗？
They live in Tokyo, remember?
寄宿监护人就更不用说了
And don't even worry about host parents.
他们被我吓坏了
I think I scared them.
神子 听着
Miko, listen.
如果你中学肄业 就没法进那个…
If you fail high school. You can't go to... uh.. to the...
大…阿…西…约… 那个词儿怎么说来着？
Uh... Una... i... Wait wait wait what's that word again?
呃 大学吗？
Uh, college?
你说话跟我父母一样
You sound like my parents.
他们不是日本人吗？
Aren't they Japanese?
你们的语言是不一样
They make speak a different language
可内容都是老一套
but you say the same things.
因为我们都是为你好
Because we want the best for you
也就是说 希望你去上学 而不是坐牢
and that means making sure you go to school, not jail.
啊喔 你又闯什么祸了？
Uho, what did you do?
听着 神子 我在成为战士之前
Look, Miko, before I became a warrior
是个工人 建筑工
I was a laborer, construction.
我能造东西 也能拆东西 可别的都不会
I can build stuff, I can break stuff. And that's it.
我喜欢拆东西！
I love breaking stuff.
我想和你一样 小隔
I want to be just like you, Bulk.
呃 干嘛要跟我一样
Uh, why would you want to be like me
其实你可以当个…医生 就像救护车
when you can be a... a medic, like Rachet.
我发现了一个新的能量脉冲
I'm detecting a fresh energon pos
地点是一个叫希腊的国家
from a nation called Greece.
是座古城 历史应该很悠久
An ancient city, quite historical, I belief.
古希腊是吗？
Ancient Greece, uh?
又要实地考察了
A field trip!
来的正是时候 击倒
It's about time, Knockout.
我不喜欢被人放鸽子
I do not enjoy being kept waiting.
路程很远的 红蜘蛛
Ahh, it was a long drive, Starscream.
我现在还在清理保险杠上的垃圾呢
I'm still picking bugs out of my grille.
是的 没错 你也是其中之一
Yes, right. You're one of those.
什么意思？
Come again?
真想不通 一个有自尊的霸天虎 怎么会选择汽车当作伪装形态呢
Never understood why any self-respecting Decepticon would choose automobile as his vehicle mode.
选飞机不是更潇洒吗？
when it could have flight.
我喜欢那种钢丝子午线轮胎
I like the way I look in steel belted radials.
我听说 威震天陛下需要点医疗协助？
I take it that lord Megatron requires a laboratory assist?
可以这么说
You might say that.
我们到了
Here we are.
太棒了！
S-weet!
好了 我们来希腊古镇要干嘛？
So, what are we doing in Greek old ville?
我要搜索能量
I am scouting energon.
你去准备你的历史报告
You are doing research for your history report.
你敢阴我 老隔？没劲！
You punked me Bulk? Not cool!
信号很强
Signal strong.
是个发掘遗址
Excavation site!
我对建筑很在行
I know construction.
从扫描结果看来 人类挖到了能量矿
According to my scanner humans had energon vans.
可他们对此一无所知
And they don't even know it.
那是塞博特恩的东西
That's Cybertronian.
很可惜 我们的前任领袖威震天 已经昏死很久了
Sadly, our inevitably former lord Megatron has been like this for some time.
经过全体人员的投票表决
But the crew took a vote and it was decided that
希望找到一个专家 让他恢复元气
an expert might put him on the road to recovery.
我的确对身体结构有点研究 红蜘蛛
I've done plenty of body-works, Starscream
但我擅长的是拆毁 不是复原
but I'm at breaking them than fixing them.
要是我的助手在就好了
Uh, would help if I had my assistant.
我把你们俩都召来了 他人呢？
I summoned both of you. Where is he?
你呼叫的时候 我们正在考察一处能量踪迹
We were halt on an energon trail when you called.
侦察完毕 打击就会来了
Breakdown will show when he's through scouting it.
古希腊人为什么要画能量收割器？
Why would ancient Greeks paint of energon harvester.
你认识那个圆球吗？
You know what that round thing is?
你好像开窍了
You are smarter than you led on.
但开窍得有点晚了
But even dumber than he looks.
打击
Breakdown.
哼哼 想我了吗？
Hehehe, miss me?
我会想念车盘的铁锈吗？
Like rest of my undercarriage.
你认识那个呆子？
You know this lunkhead?
我们打过交道
We have a history.
你还养了个宠物
And you have a pet.
它会玩接球吗？
Does it play catch?
接着！
Catch!
神子 趴下！
Miko, stay down!
哎呀
Oops.
但愿那风景画不算太值钱
Hope that pretty picture wasn't too important.
我说过 我很会拆东西
Told you I'm good at breaking things.
我替你留了一手 老隔
I always have you back, Bulk.
我把那幅画拍下来了
Got us a picture of the picture.
的确是能量收割器
It is indeed an energon harvester.
古汽车人发明了这个强大的工具
A powerful tool created by the ancients
用来吸取各种原生能量
to remove raw energon from any source.
希腊众神也认识汽车人吗？
Greek gods knew Autobots?
不
No.
古人当时通常用画来隐藏信息
The ancients often use the art of a given era to conceal messages.
这幅壁画很可能指出了收割器所在的位置
This fresco is likely a sign post indicating a harvester's location
就在这个星球的某个角落
hidden somewhere on this planet.
呃 擎天柱
Uh, Optimus.
如果收割器能吸取一切能量
If the harvester removes energon from anything
那你们体内的能量怎么办？
and you all have energon pumping inside you...
如果落入霸天虎之手
In Decepticon hands
收割器将变成毁灭性的武器
the harvester would be a devastating weapon.
你看 你毁掉那幅画太明智了
See, you are a genius to total that painting.
神子说的没错
Miko's not wrong.
没有了壁画 虎子们去哪儿找收割器？
How can the Cons find the harvester without the Fresco?
当然是高速互联网了
With high speed internet?
在图片中搜索希腊神祗和金球
If we do an image search for Greek God and Gold orb
就能搜到这个
this pops up.
在一个博物馆里
It's in a museum.
那是真货吗？
That the real deal?
联系福勒探员
Contact Agent Fowler.
这是威廉・福勒特工的电话号码
You've reached Special Agent William Fowler.
我正在进行秘密强化训练
I've currently on an intensive training retreat.
周二之前不会回来
And I'm not available until Tuesday.
我讨厌跟机器说话
I hate talking to machines.
既然福勒探员没办法出面
Without Agent Fowler's direct aid
我们就要亲自没收收割器了
we will have to confiscate the harvester on our own.
喔…“没收”？
Well, well, well, confiscate?
那是盗窃博物馆财产
As in steal museum property?
听起来是…非法行为
That sounds illegal.
我也不想触犯人类法律
I do not wish to break human law.
可一旦霸天虎得知收割器的位置
But once the Decepticons learn of the harvester's location
他们会不惜任何手段 把它据为己有
they will not hesitate to obtain it by any means necessary.
我们必须隐蔽行动
We must act covertly.
好吧 说句不好听的 擎天柱
Ehe, OK, no offense, Optimus.
让巨型机器人执行隐蔽行动实在不靠谱
But, covertly and giant robots don't really go together.
博物馆是公共场所
Museums are public.
里面有保安 还有安全摄像头
And they have guards and security cameras.
没问题！
No problem!
我们个子小 可以溜进去
We are small enough to sneak in
而且我们不是秘密势力
and we are not a government secret.
神子 我觉得这么做不太明智
Miko, I'm not sure that's wise.
但也许是我们的最佳选择 隔板
But it may be our best option, Bulkhead.
我们争论得越久
The longer we debate
给霸天虎留下的时间就越多
the more time we give to the Decepticons.
肯定就是那个
Umhm, that's definitely it.
恐怕威震天的康复工作要先放在一边了
And I'm afraid Megatron's well-being will have to wait.
收割的时候到了
It's harvest time.
汽车人 确认位置
Autobots, confirm position.
西侧搞定
Westward held.
南侧没问题
South side covered.
保持警戒
Maintain your guard.
杰克 神子 拉斐尔
Jack, Miko, Raphael
我会密切监控你们周围的情况
I will have a clear view of you.
只要拿到了收割器
Once you secure the harvester
我就让救护车把你们传送回基地
I will contact Ratchet to bridge you back to base.
我送你们绕过所有的普通入口
I'll send you bypass all points of normal entry.
不用担心会触发警报器
You won't need to worry about setting off the alarm.
但千万别碰到什么保安
But take care to avoid any security guards.
找到啦！
Oppa!
轮圈很帅嘛 24寸轮胎是吧？
Sweet rims, 24-gage?
你的分量还真够重的
You are really heavy duty
和我这位朋友一样
just like my friend here.
是虎子！
It's Cons.
他们打倒了擎天柱
They got Optimus.
什么？
What?
快走 该撤退了 兄弟们！
Come on, time to make our exit, boys.
呃…有事吗？
Uh, what's up?
你最好跟我来 小姐
You'd better come with me, miss.
坏了
Not good.
阿尔茜！
Arcee!
是声波！
It's Soundwave.
嗯 我的猎物是它
Hmm... That would be game.
虎子抢走了收割器！
The Cons have the harbester.
保安抢走了神子！
And security has Miko!
什么？我进去找她
What? I'm going in after her.
隔板 神子可能被暂时扣留
Bulkhead, Miko may be detained
但她没有任何危险
but she is safe from harm.
听着 小鬼 如果你在搞恶作剧
Look, kid, if this is some kind of a prank
告诉你 政府已经派人过来了
you need to know that the authorities are on their way.
想尽快脱身的话 快告诉我那个金球去哪儿了？
It'd go a whole lot easier for you if you just told me what happened to the sphere.
我要准备我的历史报告
I was researching my history report
结果忘了闭馆时间 就被关在里面了
I just lost track of time and got locked in here after closing.
那你的历史报告是什么内容？
So what's your history report about?
我很想知道
I'd love to know.
呃…
Eh...
红蜘蛛极有可能使用收割器 迅速收集到巨大能量
In all likelihood Starscream will use the harvester to gather as much energon as quickly as he can
他会选择星球上无法常规开采的能量矿
from the planet's otherwise un-minable energon deposits.
一定要小心行动
Approach with extreme caution.
红蜘蛛一定希望把收割器用在我们身上
Starscream will not hesitate to turn the harvester on any one of us.
隔板
Bulkhead
你最好留在这里
it is best that you remain here.
让我去博物馆救出神子吗？
So I can bust Miko out of the museum?
让你协助救护车
So you can help Ratchet.
你虽然是神子的保镖
You may be Miko's guardian
但眼下她需要的是人类的帮忙
but she requires human assistance.
最好请福勒探员走一趟
Agent Fowler remains our best option.
这是威廉・福勒特工的电话号码
You've reached special Agent William Fowler.
我正在进行秘密强化训练
I'm currently on an intensive training retreat
周二之前不会回来
and I’m not available until Tuesday.
还是无人接听
Still not answered.
福勒肯定是在海景别墅享福呢
Fowler's lounging around some poolside cabana.
隔板 那个我还有用呐！
Bulkhead, I needed that!
我们能救出神子
We can free Miko
只要把收割器归还博物馆就行了
if we can just return that harvester to the museum.
好让霸天虎再去偷走吗？
So that Decepticons can steal it all over again?
我真是笨到家了！
I am so dumb!
那我们该怎么帮神子？
So how are we going to help Miko?
把这个复制品还给博物馆
By returning this replica to the museum
这东西本来很快就能做好了
The construction of which would be going a whole lot faster
可隔板把我的车床砸了个稀烂！
if Bulkhead hadn't just mangled my frame wielder!
我们已经当过入侵者和窃贼了
We're already trespassers and thieves
再加一条伪造罪也无所谓
why not add forgery to the list?
我真不该带神子去那个…
I wish I had never taken Miko to the...
除了收割器的壁画 我们在遗迹还发现了别的东西
the painting of the harvester isn't the only thing we found in those ruins.
我没听懂
I'm sorry?
红蜘蛛可不笨
Starscream is not dumb.
不管他有什么工具
No matter what kind of tool he has
他总想走捷径
he is going to take the easy route.
干嘛还要去开山修路呢
Why move maintains now
手头上不是有这么多现成的能量吗？
when we have a motherload of energon right here for the taking
真要感谢古代汽车人留下的这份礼物
courtesy of this gift from the ancient Autobots.
呃 其实 红蜘蛛指挥官
Uh, actually, commander Starscream
送礼的人是打击和在下
it was a gift from breakdown and myself.
喔 那么多能量 都收集在这个小容器里边
Oh, that energon, in such a tiny vessel.
那帮远古的汽车人的确心灵手巧 红蜘蛛陛下
Those ancient Autobots never missed a trick, lord Starscream.
呃 糟了
Um, scrap.
去去就来！
Back for seconds.
你个头很大
You are a big one.
吸收时间要长一点了
This could take a while.
等等 你要干嘛？
Wait, what are you doing?
干我的老本行！
What I do best!
拆东西！
Breaking things!
他好像很喜欢接受惩罚
He is a glutton for punishment.
打吗？
Fight?
嗯 撤吧
Um, drive.
嘿
Hey.
当然了 首先要知道什么是机器之神
And of course there is this whole principle of Deus ex Machina.
呃 就是用机器制造的神
Uh, the god from the machine.
在希腊戏剧里面 充当神的角色突然出现 解决所有问题
It's that part in Greek story telling when some character shows up out of the blue to make everything right.
是吗 小姑娘
That's so, young lady.
我敢肯定 警察会喜欢听你编的这些历史故事的
Well, I am sure the police will want to hear all about you history report.
我是特工威廉・福勒
Special Agent William Fowler
失窃财产已经被找到 并归还给博物馆了
the stolen property has been located and restored in museum premises.
这女孩我带走
The girl comes with me.
你的手机掉了
You dropped you cell phone.
在地上找到的 就在你的历史报告旁边
Found on the floor right next to your history report.
你走吧
Off you go.
来得正好 老隔！
Good timing, Bulk.
那些野史我都讲完了
I was running out of history factoids-
都快要编不下去了！
-stuff I didn't even know I knew.
看来你也有点开窍了
Looks like you are smarter than you led on?
压力就是动力
Under pressure.
我也一样
Me, too.
一定得赶快把历史报告写完
Can't wait to finish my history report.
我要详细论述汽车人和古文明接触的那段历史
I'm gonna write all about how the Autobots interacted with ancient civilizations.
呃 那个可不能保证你上大学 神子
Uh, I'm not so sure that will get you into college, Miko.